deputy.com 2018-01-31

# Privacy Policy | Deputy

_Last updated 26th Aug, 2016_

Deputy values and respects your privacy, as a result we have updated our Privacy Policy to be in line with the current law. This Privacy Policy aims to clearly outline our policies and procedures for collecting, using, storing and disclosing your personal information. It is important to Deputy that its customers retain their privacy when using our product. To protect the information you share we follow the globally acceptable practices in customer privacy and data storage.

We ask you to read this Privacy Policy to ensure you have a good understanding of how we treat your personal information. In conjunction with this Privacy Policy we ask that you read our [Terms of Use](https://www.deputy.com/terms/use/), in doing so you understand and acknowledge the Deputy Privacy Policy and Terms of Use.

Users can access the Deputy application (the “Application”) through our website www.deputy.com, subdomain (*.deputy.com), through applications on devices, through APIs, and through third-parties. A “Device” is any computer used to access the Deputy Application, including without limitation a desktop, laptop, mobile phone, tablet, or other consumer electronic device.

This Privacy Policy governs your access of the Deputy Application, regardless of how you access it, and by using our Services you consent to the collection, transfer, processing, storage, disclosure and other uses described in this Privacy Policy. All of the different forms of data, content, and information described below are collectively referred to as “information”.

### 1\. Information you provide, how we Collect & Store it.

Deputy will collect and store certain personal information in order for you to obtain the best use of the Application.

 **1.a: Information You Provide**

When you register an account as a business or as a general user, we may collect and store personal information, such as your name, phone number, D.O.B, gender, credit card, or other billing information, email address and home and business postal addresses. In addition if you choose to upload a profile photo this will also be stored. You may also ask us to import your contacts by giving us access to your third party services (for example, your email account) or to use your social networking information if you give us access to your account on social network connection services. When you invite others to join your Deputy account, we send them a one-time email invitation. We may also receive Personal Information (for example, your email address) through other users, if they have invited you to their Deputy account.

 **1.b: Information We Collect**

 **Files** – We collect and store any files you upload, download, or create (records) within the Deputy Application. These may include links to documents held outside the Deputy application, photo images captured by the Deputy application or direct entries into the Deputy applications.

 **Log Data** – When you use the Application, we automatically record information from your Device, its software, and your activity using the Services. This may include the Device’s Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, the web page visited before you came to our website, information you search for on our website, locale preferences, identification numbers associated with your Devices, your mobile carrier, date and time stamps associated with transactions, system configuration information, metadata concerning your Files, and other interactions with the Service.

 **Cookies** – We also use “cookies” to collect information and improve our Services. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your Device. We may use “persistent cookies” to save your registration ID and login password for future logins to the Service. We may use “session ID cookies” to enable certain features of the Service, to better understand how you interact with the Service and to monitor aggregate usage and web traffic routing on the Service. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all aspects of the Application.

 **Online Tracking**  – We may use internal and external analytic and product platforms to better understand usage patterns on our website so that we can improve the design and usability of our products. Some web browsers may transmit “do-no-track” signals to websites with which the browser communicates. Our website does not currently respond to these “do-not-track” signals.

 **1.c: How We Store It**

Any Personal information as outlined above will be stored within the Deputy application. This information will be backed up to the nearest data storage location within that customers country, not offshore.

### 2\. How We Use It

To allow you access to the Application, to personalize and improve your experience and to provide you with software updates and product announcements.

 **Geo-Location Information** – Some Devices allow applications to access real-time location-based information (for example, GPS). We may use this information to optimize your experience. Also, some of the information we collect from a Device, for example IP address, can be used to approximate a Device’s location.

 **Analytics** – Information captured (log data) may be used analytically to understand the user statistics of the Application with the view of improving the Application.

### 3\. Information Sharing & Disclosure

Your right to privacy is always utmost in our mind. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may use the information we collect and store in a statistical way in order to optimise your usage of the Deputy application from time to time, as outlined above.

  1.  **Your Use** – We will display your Personal Information in your profile page, this may be accessed by other persons to whom you are connected within your organisation depending on their access level. We may share or disclose your information with your consent, for example if you use a third party application to access your account (see below).
  2.  **Service Providers, Business Partners and Others** – We may use certain trusted third party companies and individuals to help us provide, analyze, and improve the Service (including but not limited to data storage, maintenance services, database management, web analytics, payment processing, and improvement of the Service’s features). These third parties may have access to your information only for purposes of performing these tasks on our behalf and under obligations similar to those in this Privacy Policy. As of the date this policy went into effect, we use Amazon Web Services. (you can view their privacy policy here http://aws.amazon.com/privacy/)
  3.  **Third-Party Applications** – We may share your information with a third party application with your consent, for example when you choose to access Deputy through such an application. We are not responsible for what those parties do with your information, so you should make sure you trust the application and that it has a privacy policy acceptable to you before allowing this feature to be employed.
  4.  **Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement Requests; Protection of Deputy.com’s Rights** – We may disclose to parties outside Deputy, files stored in your Application and information about you that we collect when we have a good faith belief that disclosure is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with a law, regulation or compulsory legal request; or (b) to protect Deputy’s property rights. If we provide your Deputy files to a law enforcement agency as set forth above, we will remove Deputy’s encryption from the files before providing them to law enforcement.
  5.  **Business Transfers** – If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, your information may be transferred as part of that transaction, but we will notify you (for example, via email and/or a prominent notice on our website) of any change in control or use of your Personal Information or Files, or if either become subject to a different Privacy Policy. We will also notify you of choices you may have regarding the information.
  6.  **Non-private or Non-Personal Information** – We may disclose your non-private, aggregated, or otherwise non-personal information, such as usage statistics of our Service.
  7.  **Information shared with agents and service providers** –  we may share information we collect or you provide to us with the agents or third party service providers of Deputy who require the information to provide their services to Deputy and such agents or third party service providers are not allowed to use the information for any other purpose.

### 4\. Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, you may contact us via experience@deputy.com. We may retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. Consistent with these requirements, we will try to delete your information quickly upon request and if desired make it available to you. Please note, however, that there might be latency in deleting information from our servers and backed-up versions might exist after deletion. In addition, we do not delete from our servers files that you have in common with other users.

### 5\. Deletion/Editing of Data

We shall not delete or edit your stored information without a direct request from the holder of the data, if we do receive a request by a single person that is not a business owner, we shall direct that single person to the organisation they belong to, so that the request can be validated and then forwarded to Deputy for action.

Our Application offers publicly accessible community services such as blogs, forums, and wikis. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. Your posts may remain even after you cancel your account.

### 7\. Security

Deputy has taken strong measures to protect the security of your information against data loss, misuse, unauthorised access or disclosure and destruction.

When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our payment pages, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL) which is PCI DSS compliant.

### 8\. Changes to our Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy may change from time to time. If we make a change to this privacy policy that we believe materially reduces your rights, we will provide you with notice (for example, by email). And we may provide notice of changes in other circumstances as well. By continuing to use the Application after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy.

### 9\. More information or Disputes

If you would like further information on your privacy and personal information that we store, collect or use, please contact privacy@deputy.com.

If you have a concern or dispute regarding this policy, these privacy terms or the personal information we store, collect or use, please contact privacy@deputy.com. Please outline to us your concerns and or dispute and our legal team or Deputy representative will be in touch to discuss the matter.
